<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tallya Lutfak</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Tallya Lutfak</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro to Python Basics and For Loops</title>
      <link>/blog/learning-python-basics-and-indexing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/learning-python-basics-and-indexing/</guid>
      <description>Python is a programming language, one of many, that is well developed and widely used by data scientists. It is known for being an easily readable language and is popular amoung the machine learning community. I’m assuming if you are reading this blog you are somewhat familar but some background information never hurts. Today, we are going to explore the backbone basics of Python. First, we are going to establish the main data types that exist in Python: intergers, float, string, and bool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resume/</guid>
      <description>TALLYA LUTFAKtlutfak@gmail.comAustin, Texas 78705 (409) 201-1651
EDUCATIONThe University of Texas at Austin Bachelor of Science and Arts, Biology May 2021
Minor: Religious Studies
EXPERIENCETejas Ear, Nose, and Throat:Receptionist/Secretary; Round Rock, Texas June 2017-August 2017 June 2018-August 2018Collaborated with the office manager to integrate a new scheduling program which increasedthe doctors daily patients by over 50%
Catalogued over 500 patient files into alphabetical order and then scanned them electronically intothe company’s database</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Income and Homicide Rates</title>
      <link>/project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/</guid>
      <description>Tallya Lutfak tl26427The datasets I used for my project were 1)The Homicide Rates and Deaths Across US States and 2) The Gini Coeffiecent used to measure Inequality across States. I read an article recently that Income Inequality was a contributing factor to Homicide so decided to explore that relationship. The Dataset I called ‘Homicide’ contained 5 variables:YEAR, STATE, DEATH, RATE,URL. The same data was collected across five different years of 2017, 2016, 2015, 2014, 2005.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predicting Effectivenss of Cognitive Therapy Program on Depressed Patients</title>
      <link>/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project2/</guid>
      <description>The dataset I used for my project was the Beat the Blues (BtheB) dataset. It is a longitudinal study from a clinical trial that contains data on the effects of a multimedia program “Beat the Blues”, that serves as cognitive therapy, on depression levels of depressed patients. The dataset has 100 observations and 8 variables. The first variable is a catergorical variable that specfies whether or not the patient took anti-depressent drugs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>Projects Here are my recent projects: - Data Wrangling and Exploratory Analysis Project - Modeling, Inference, Prediction Project </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>